<NIKITA AVEROCHKIN>

</FRONTEND DEVELOPER>

+7 915 543 85 25

aser-14@bk.ru

• Voronezh, Russia

Portfolio website

Hey! I'm creative and constantly growing developer with more than three years of experience who loves crafting products that people love. I'm eager to apply my expertise, solving extraordinary problems and bringing profit to customers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

ITI | Moscow, Russia (Remote) May 2023 — Current

I was developing a corporate application portals:

- Worked on diverse projects: on React.js and on HP Service Manager using ES5 JavaScript.
- Carried out organizational tasks of the team.

I have completed over 30% of all tasks assigned to the team on utilized by thousands applications and implemented crucial functionality to beta React.js project. Moreover, I essentially enhanced the workflow and team productivity by conducting daily briefings, retrospectives and creating full project documentation.

Stack: React.js, JavaScript, CSS, Styled Components, Webpack, HP Service Manager, RAD

Frontend Developer

Calendaria | Almaty, Kazakhstan (Remote) November 2022 — May 2023

I was a frontend lead of enterprise portal, including:

- Designing frontend architecture on React.js and application layout from scratch.
- Analysing of technical assignment and project needs.
- Coordinating of the work of a junior frontend developer, interacting with various teams.

I successfully accomplished full development process on time, completely satisfied the customer's requirements achieving all project goals. My efforts have resulted in an application that is actively maintained and used by hundreds of users.

Stack: React.js, TypeScript Redux-toolkit, React-JSS, Ant Design, Webpack

Frontend Developer

Tecom | Nizhny Novgorod, Russia (Remote) November 2021 — November 2022

I was working on several projects: My role included:

- Development of key libraries, including a corporate Ulkit with storybook, as well as a library of ready-made utilities.
- Fixing, refactoring and writing new logic on React.js.

 Implement unit and e2e tests to ensure the core application reliability.

I realized ~90% of the required functionality in editorlike widgets and received positive feedback from customers. I made the core application several times more reliable due to my tests, which helped the team fix the main problems. My efforts in developing libraries have made development faster and more efficient.

Stack: React.js, React-JSS, Material UI, Intl, Redux, Reselect, Jest, Playwright, Ierna

Frontend Developer

Julius | London, United Kingdom (Remote)
December 2020 - November 2021

I was preparing the company's main React.js project for release into production. For this I:

- Redesigned the layout of almost all the components, improved app accessibility.
- Developed many features, such as theming and internalization and components, such as tables and dashboards.

I significantly accelerated the frontend development due to my SCSS modifications, improved a lot of core functionality, quality of user experience making the app pixel-perfect identical to Figma and app accessibility up to 90%. I successfully collaborated with team members and motivated them to achieve collective goals.

Stack: React.js, TypeScript, SCSS, Ant Design, GraphQL, React Relay

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Voronezh State University

2019-2023 | Voronezh, Russia

Faculty: Applied math, informatics and mechanics. Direction: Fundamental informatics and information technologies

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (FLUENT), RUSSIAN (NATIVE)